Should we spend our summer break having fun?
暑假我們要不要出去玩？
Sure, sure.
好啊好啊
I want to have more fun with Airi.
我還想再跟小愛莉一起玩
Huh? Sorry, what were you saying?
抱歉 妳剛說什麼
I said I wanted to have more fun with Airi.
我說我還想再跟小愛莉一起玩
Airi is so cute.
小愛莉好可愛哦
But I have no idea why Airi suddenly pounced on me.
但不知道為什麼她突然撲到我身上
I'm sorry about that.
真不好意思
No worries. She's cute.
沒關係 她很可愛
Aren't you going to invite Sajo as well?
妳們不約佐城嗎
Although he has not been pestering to Natsukawa as much lately.
雖然他最近很少出現在夏川身邊
Is he embarrassed?
他是不是覺得不好意思啊？
Because Natsukawa is so popular now.
因為夏川同學太受歡迎了
Is that so?
還是說...
I wonder if he has a reason.
他發生什麼事了嗎
He must have had a reason for giving up after being so persistent.
畢竟他以前那麼執著 現在卻一百八十度大轉變
I don't know why either.
我也不知道為什麼
It is indeed strange.
大家果然會覺得奇怪啊
(Should we open it and take a look? Should we? To see what's inside?)
(要打開看看裡面裝了什麼嗎？)
So she is Natsukawa Aika.
她就是夏川愛華
Everyone remarks on her striking appearance.
她跟大家說的一樣 真的很引人注目
I believe she has some utility.
她應該有利用價值吧
Are you looking for Natsukawa?
妳們找夏川有什麼事嗎
W-Who are you?
你誰啊
Please don't approach people from behind.
請你別突然從人家身後搭話好嗎
Do you know who I am?
你知道我是誰嗎
Unlike you, I am noble--
我跟你不一樣 人家我可是高貴的...
So this is how the noble will scream.
原來身分高貴的人也會這樣鬼叫啊
Wh-What are you doing!
你這人怎麼這樣啊
How could Marika do something like that?
茉莉花同學怎麼可能會鬼叫
Unreasonable! People on the east side are hopeless!
有夠沒禮貌 東側的人果然沒救了
Let's go! Don't bother with this kind of person.
我們走 不要理這種人
Agreed, goodbye!
贊成 告辭了
Let's go quickly.
我們快走吧
What's the fuss?
你們在吵什麼
Sajo, what happened?
小佐城 發生什麼事了
No, nothing.
沒什麼啦
Just three strange young ladies showed up.
就是來了奇妙的大小姐三人組
Three young ladies?
大小姐三人組？
It takes all sorts to make the world.
這世界上真是什麼樣的人都有
Wh-Why are you here?
你...怎麼在這裡
Good morning, Natsukawa.
夏川早安
Do you think it is a little chilly today?
妳不覺得今天有點冷嗎
Is it?
會...會嗎
Is it my illusion?
是我的錯覺嗎
W-Wait for me!
你...等等我
What's wrong with him? Geez.
搞什麼啊 真是的
What's--
怎麼了...
Natsukawa!
夏川！
What?
什麼
Huh?
啊？
A tender and juicy man.
嫩得出水的優質男子
You seem to be dying.
你怎麼一副死人臉啊
Don't mock me.
妳用得著補我一刀嗎
What a bummer.
真倒霉
Here you go.
這給你
This handkerchief has not been used.
這...這條手帕我還沒用過
Take it and clean yourself.
你拿去擦吧
No need. I'm too embarrassed to use it.
不用了 怎麼好意思
J-Just take it.
你...你就拿去啦
You can use this too.
這也給你用吧
So stinky! It stinks! It smells like sweat!
這也太臭了吧 一股汗臭味
Isn't this the one you just used? Spare me.
拜託不要拿你用過的給我好嗎
Is he asleep? Is he asleep? No way.
你現在是睡著了嗎 不會吧
He fell asleep too quickly.
他也太快入睡了吧
What's wrong? There was a loud noise just now.
怎麼了 剛才好大的聲響
I haven't fallen asleep yet.
我還沒睡好嗎
From 1789 to 1795,
法國大革命是一場資產階級革命
the French Revolution was a bourgeois revolution.
從1789年持續到1795年
Damn, I fell asleep.
糟糕 我真的睡著了
World History. Is it already the third lesson?
世界史...已經第三節課了嗎
I should act as if I have been awake for quite some time.
我還是裝作一副早就醒了的樣子吧
It seems I didn't sleep well.
啊 這個感覺很不妙
My head hurts. It hurts!
我的頭好痛啊 痛死了
Sajo, are you awake?
小佐城 你醒了嗎
Sajo, you finally woke up.
佐城同學 你終於睡醒了啊
The students informed me as to why you were wearing a sports shirt.
我聽說了你穿運動服的原因
I can understand you're a bit upset.
我能理解你心情不太愉快
But you can't stop listening to the lecture because of that.
但這不是讓你放棄聽課的理由
Yes.
是
-Madam… -What is it?
-老師... -怎麼了
C-Can I go to the school infirmary?
我可以去一趟保健室嗎
Go ahead.
你去吧
Find another student to show you the notes later.
之後再找個同學把筆記借你看吧
Yes.
是
Hey! Sajo?
喂 小佐城
Sajo, are you okay? Sajo?
佐城同學你沒事吧 佐城同學？
You're quite an interesting guy.
你這傢伙還真有趣
I started pretending when I was in junior high.
升上國二時 我開始偽裝自己
I learned to keep my true feelings hidden.
我學會隱藏自己的真心話
I learned to look at things sarcastically.
學會了用嘲諷的角度看待事物
I thought this was what they meant by maturing.
我以為這就是所謂的長大成人
Over here, Sajo. Come quickly.
佐城 你快過來這裡啦
Alright, I'm coming.
好 我這就來了
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
SCHOOL INFIRMARY
(保健室)
Oh my, so he passed out like this.
唉呀 原來他是這樣昏倒的
Such a sinful performance.
真是罪孽深重的表演啊
How can it be a performance, Madam?
怎麼會是表演呢 老師
After all, he doesn't appear to have been hit on the head.
畢竟他不像是撞到頭
Although he has a fever, he should be fine.
雖然有點發燒 但應該沒什麼大礙
He's still sleeping now.
他現在還在睡
Would you like to take a look?
妳們想看他一眼嗎
Okay.
想
I believe this is the first time we have seen his sleeping face.
我們好像是第一次看他睡覺的樣子吧
So you were worried about him?
妳是在擔心他嗎
I-I…
我…我只是...
Alright, alright, the next lesson is about to start.
好了 下一節課快開始了哦
You should get back to the classroom.
妳們快回教室吧
Sorry.
不好意思
Don't worry.
妳們放心吧
Damn it.
可惡
Oh, you're awake?
喔 你醒啦
You passed out in class.
你在教室昏倒了
Your classmates carried you here.
是你同學們扶你過來的
I see.
這樣啊
Did I catch a cold?
我是感冒了嗎
Yeah. I took your temperature earlier and it was 38.6 degrees Celsius.
嗯 剛才量了體溫是38.6度
The temperature may still rise.
有可能還會再更燒
No way.
怎麼會這樣
I was fine this morning.
我早上完全沒事啊
Is it because your tense nerves relaxed suddenly?
是因為你神經緊繃過頭了吧
You must be exhausted.
你一定是積勞成疾了
Exhausted…
疲勞...
This includes mental exhaustion.
精神上的疲勞也算哦
Take this.
這給你
Sleep a little longer.
你再睡一下吧
Okay.
好的
Why am I so worried about him?
我為什麼會這麼擔心他
Look, look. No way.
快看 不會吧
Look at that.
在那邊
She's a goddess. I'm dying.
簡直跟神一樣 誰受得了
Shinomiya!
四之宮學姊
STUDENT COUNCIL Wow, you look so cool.
哇 學姊好帥氣
Hello.
大家好
Excuse me, are you Ashida?
請問妳是蘆田同學嗎
Y-Yes. L-Long time no see.
是...是的 好...好久不見
I have to talk to Sajo.
我有事想找佐城
Oh, he…
他啊...
Actually, he…
不瞞妳說
He passed out?
他昏倒了？
It seems you haven't told Kaede yet.
看樣子妳們應該還沒有告訴楓？
We plan to visit Sajo…
我們打算再去探望小佐城...不是
We plan to visit Sajo once more.
我們打算再去探望佐城同學
Do you want me to ask him how he is doing?
要我幫妳問問他的狀況嗎
No need.
不用
We will pay him a visit after I notify Kaede.
我打算先通知楓 然後再跟楓一起去探望他
O-Okay.
好的
Thank you.
謝謝妳
You've always admired her, haven't you?
妳一直很崇拜學姊對吧
Yeah, why are you pinching my face?
嗯 妳幹嘛捏我的臉
So light!
好輕哦
Sajo's bag is so light!
小佐城的書包超輕的耶
Don't shake it around like that.
妳別這樣亂甩啦
Oops, it really is light.
啊 真的很輕耶
Should we open it and take a look? Should we? To see what's inside?
要打開看看裡面裝了什麼嗎
It is not right to just go through someone else's belongings.
不行 怎麼可以亂翻別人的東西
What if we find some adult magazines? That wouldn't be good.
要是翻到什麼A書就不好了
How can there be…
那怎麼可能...
Is that possible?
有可能嗎...
Is there or not? I'm so excited.
到底有沒有呢？好緊張哦
I told you I won't look!
我說了我不會看的
You're not looking? Really?
妳真的不看一下嗎
-No. -This is a golden opportunity.
-不看 -機會難得耶
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《滿懷美夢的少年是現實主義者》
SCHOOL INFIRMARY
(保健室)
We're coming in.
打擾了
Huh?
咦
Sajo, are you awake?
小佐城 你醒著嗎
Shh!
噓
Shh.
安靜
He is probably still sleeping.
他應該還在睡吧
I wonder if he's feeling better.
不知道他好點沒
Wh-What? You should say something if you are awake.
什...什麼嘛 你明明醒著幹嘛不出聲
Can't you sleep?
你睡不著嗎
No.
沒有
Do you need anything?
你需要什麼嗎
Here's some Pocari Sweat.
這裡有寶礦力
Sorry.
抱歉
I have shocked everyone.
我驚動到大家了
Not at all.
不會啦
What's wrong? You're acting a bit weird.
你怎麼好像有點怪怪的
What's that weird?
哪裡怪了
If you ask me, I…
你這樣問我也...
-Wataru! -Sajo!
-阿涉 -小佐城
I'm sorry. I have a bit of a headache.
糟糕 我頭好痛
You don't have to try hard to talk.
你...你不用勉強自己說話
Don't touch me!
妳別碰我
Wh-Why?
你...幹嘛啊
I don't want to infect others.
我不想傳染給別人
I don't want to pass it to Airi.
例如小愛莉之類
Huh? Um.
喔...這樣啊
I don't want to make others suffer.
我不想害別人痛苦
SCHOOL INFIRMARY
(保健室)
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
等一下等一下...
What's going on? What's happening?
剛才那是怎麼回事
The feeble Sajo is…
小佐城虛弱的樣子真是...
We can't say things like this. It's too unserious.
妳...別講這種話 太不恰當了
We didn't come to visit him for this.
我們又不是為了這個才來探望他的
What's wrong with you guys?
妳們兩個怎麼了
-Shinomiya! -Sister!
-四之宮學姊 -楓姊姊
STUDENT COUNCIL S-Sorry.
不...不好意思
We've been waiting for you both.
我們久候兩位多時了
I-Is that so?
喔...是嗎
How is he?
他還好嗎
Um…
這個嘛...
Sis, it's you.
是老姊啊
How are you feeling?
你還好嗎
My head hurts a lot.
我頭很痛
I heard you passed out?
我聽說你昏倒了
I'm fine now.
已經沒事了
You dummy.
你這蠢蛋
Let me see.
我看看
So cool.
手好冰
Is there anything you want?
你有想要什麼東西嗎
I will buy it for you.
我去買給你
I'll go call Mom.
我去打電話給媽媽
You probably haven't informed Mom yet.
反正你一定還沒跟她說吧
I'll be back soon.
我去去就回
Wataru…
阿涉...
Good morning, everyone.
大家早安
The morning meeting is about to start.
朝會要開始了哦
Sajo is absent today, right?
佐城同學今天請假對吧
COLD MEDICINE
(感冒藥)
Na-Natsukawa? Ashida!
夏...夏川跟蘆田？
You finally picked up!
你終於來了
Were you sleeping just now?
你該不會在睡覺吧
You really dare to come.
妳們還真敢來
"You really dare to come…"?
你說什麼真敢來啊
FEELS GOOD TO BE ALIVE
(活著真好)
WHAT'S THE MEANING? WHAT'S WRONG? STILL ALIVE? If you are kidding,
(什麼意思 怎麼了 你還活著嗎) 你要是想開玩笑
DEAD? HUH? REALLY? act like it.
(你死了嗎 咦 真假) 就好好開玩笑啊
Why did you leave a confusing message and then leave?
怎麼可以講完一句話就無故消失
COLD MEDICINE
(感冒藥)
I had hundreds of unread messages.
居然有上百則未讀訊息
DEAD? HUH? REALLY? Sorry, I fell asleep. Send.
(你死了嗎 咦 真假) 抱歉 我睡著了 發送
WHAT? SLEEP FOR A LIFETIME. DON'T WAKE UP.
(啥 睡一輩子吧你 別醒來了)
You asked for it.
你活該
Aika was the one who decided to pay you a visit.
是小愛主動說要來探望你的哦
W-Wait a minute, Kei!
圭... 妳幹嘛啦
Really?
真的嗎
B-Because you got all wet for me…
畢竟你是因為我才渾身濕透的...
No, it's nothing.
總之就是這樣啦
Fortunately, Aika knows where you live.
幸虧小愛知道小佐城家在哪
I-It's because I asked Yamazaki before.
那只是因為之前山崎同學告訴過我
Thank you.
謝謝
W-We should go, Kei.
圭...我們回家吧
Huh? You are leaving now?
妳們這麼快就要走了？
Knowing you're okay is enough for me.
我們知道你沒事就夠了吧
Huh? Is that so?
啊 是嗎
Here, this is for you. A consolation gift.
那這個探病禮品給你
You don't need to see us out. Remember to lock the door.
你不用送我們了 待會記得鎖門哦
Okay.
喔 好
You're here again. What is it this time?
妳這次又想來幹嘛啊
You're always like this.
你這人怎麼老是...
Na-Natsukawa Aika!
夏川愛華同學
I have something to discuss with you!
人家有事要找妳
Excuse me, what's the matter?
妳...有什麼事嗎
Even if you are good, in second place,
就算妳成績優異 排名全年級第二
and a little bit cute--
然後又長得有一點點可愛
You're indeed very cute.
還真的是很可愛呢
Huh? Uh… Thank you.
咦 呃...謝謝妳
I-I bestow upon you, who is slightly above average,
看在妳稍微有一點優秀的份上 我決定特別賞賜妳一個權利
the right to cheer for the top student in the grade, Shinonome Claudine Marika.
讓妳替東雲・克勞蒂娜・茉莉花 也就是全年級第一的我本人加油
So just cheer for her?
妳就幫她加個油吧
Huh? Cheer on!
那...那妳加油囉
No, no!
不對
That's not what I meant!
人家才不是這個意思
Natsukawa!
夏川同學
You have to cheer for me to
為了讓我能成為下屆學生會長
become the next student council president.
妳要支持我啦
Huh? Can a first-year student be the student council president?
咦 一年級也能當學生會長嗎
Let me explain.
這個由我來說明
STUDENT COUNCIL OFFICE
(學生會辦公室)
All student council positions are open to all grades,
學生會的所有職位
whether self-nominated or nominated by others.
無論年級高低或自薦他薦都可以參選
Hi, the walking student handbook.
妳真是活生生的學生手冊啊
Kaoruko, I doubt he is complimenting you.
薰子同學... 我想他應該不是在誇獎妳
Having said that, first-year students are typically at a disadvantage.
話雖如此 一年級的學生通常都不佔優勢
Since most people think only senior students can be student representatives.
因為大家普遍認為 只有高年級生才配當學生代表
That makes sense.
這倒也沒錯啊
The next student council president should be Senior Kai, right?
照理來說 下屆學生會長應該會是甲斐學長吧
Senior Kai stated that he doesn't want to be student council president.
不 甲斐學長本人已出面否認這點
At the moment, no second-year students have expressed interest
目前在二年級的學生之中
in running for student council president.
也沒人表示要參選學生會長
However, there will still be candidates at that time,
話雖如此 屆時還是會出現候選人吧
so I must gather like-minded individuals to assist me
所以我必須在那之前
in becoming the student council president before then.
召集有志一同的支持者 幫助我成為學生會長
In a nutshell, you want Natsukawa to be your ambassador.
總而言之 妳是想讓夏川擔任妳的宣傳大使嗎
You could say that.
也可以這麼說
What a terrible move.
這招太爛了吧
What did you say?
你說什麼
I seem to have heard some nonsense.
我似乎聽到了一些胡言亂語
Can you explain why you said that?
請問你為什麼這麼說
Because Natsukawa is too noticeable.
因為夏川她太引人注目了
You're called Clau…Clauma, right?
妳是叫克勞瑪蒂來著嗎
What? Clauma--
什麼克勞瑪...
If you make Natsukawa your ambassador, the students will think,
如果夏川當妳的宣傳大使 大家就會覺得
"Is it that person who is running? Why isn't Natsukawa?"
“原來要參選的是那個人 不是夏川同學啊？”
T-That's rude!
你很失禮耶
As a boy, I believe that
就我作為一名男生的意見來說
bringing Natsukawa in will make you appear insignificant.
拉攏夏川反而會讓妳相形失色哦
Wh-What do you mean by that?
你這話是什麼意思
Natsukawa is cuter than you.
因為夏川比妳可愛
I'll take my leave now.
那我就此告辭了
How dare you…
妳竟敢...
Marika!
茉莉花同學
We should…
我們還是...
Probably leave.
撤退比較好
This time we will leave. This time!
這次我們就先行告退了 就這次而已
Goodbye, everyone.
各位再見
Sajo, Sajo.
小佐城啊小佐城
Huh? What? What's the matter?
什麼 現在是怎樣
It is all because you said some shameless words.
還不是因為小佐城你那番不得了的話
Shameless words?
不得了的話？
You said Aika is cuter.
你說小愛比較可愛啊
Natsukawa must have heard these words a lot.
這種話 夏川早就聽到耳朵都長“繭子“了吧
Why are you still talking about it after I have said it so many times?
我都不知道說過幾百遍了 妳現在才說這個幹嘛
Anyone would be embarrassed if you said it so openly.
畢竟你說得那麼理直氣壯
And the time and place are just right.
再加上天時地利人和的幫助
But Natsukawa's face is now as red as "tendon" meat.
不過現在夏川的臉 的確是紅得跟“腱子“肉一樣
Sajo, put your boring joke aside.
小佐城 你真的很愛冷笑話耶
Don't say things that will make people shy!
你別說這種會讓人害臊的話好嗎
I don't think you are over your cold yet!
我看你是感冒還沒好吧
So cute.
好可愛
D-D-D-D--
你...你...
Don't look!
討厭啦
SUMMER VACATION IS COMING. I WANT TO PLAY. GO STUDY. For high school students about to
(暑假來啦 我要大玩特玩 去唸書啦) 即將迎接暑假的高中生
embark on their summer vacation, the most important thing,
如果想要適度豐富自己的生活 有樣不可或缺的東西
yes, is money.
沒錯 那就是錢
A sense of meticulous calculation
總覺得這種精打細算的感覺
is rather cool.
還頗帥氣的
NO AGE LIMIT, NO EXPERIENCE REQUIRED, RECRUITING PEOPLE WHO LIKE TO READ. I will be able to get paid while also gaining valuable work experience.
(年齡經驗不拘 招募愛書的人) 還可以增加社會經驗 真是一石二鳥
I looked everywhere on the Internet and in job magazines before I found this place.
我找遍網路跟徵才雜誌 終於找到了這份打工
BINAN BOOKSTORE, SECOND-HAND BOOK TRADING
(濱南書店 二手書交易)
Are you really okay with this?
你真的可以接受嗎
That's enough.
我很滿足
Even though the hourly wage is not that great.
這裡的時薪明明不太誘人
Because I didn't want that much pocket money.
因為我也沒特別想要那麼多零用錢
I will be in charge of estimating value, putting prices on books,
估價跟貼標價
and managing stock. You will organize books and serve customers.
還有庫存管理是由我負責 書本整理跟招呼客人就麻煩你了
That's all?
真的這樣就夠了嗎
Being willing to assist me in serving customers is already a god-like existence.
你願意幫我招呼客人 對我來說就很神了
God?
神...
I see, "God", huh?
原來如此 是神啊
There seems to be a lot to learn about that, too.
這方面似乎也是一門很深的學問啊
BINAN BOOKSTORE, SECOND-HAND BOOK TRADING
(濱南書店 二手書交易)